Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to another advanced lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的另一节高级课程。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And my name is Erica.
我是 Erica。
So, today we're bringing you another advanced lesson and this time it's kind of historical.
所以，今天我们带来另一节高级课程，这次有点历史感。
Like the name suggests, we are listening in as a president says goodbye to the nation
就像名字暗示的那样，我们正在听一位总统向全国告别，
before he steps down from his role as president.
在他卸任总统职务之前。
Now actually this dialogue is very much based on President Eisenhower's farewell speech.
实际上，这段对话很大程度上基于艾森豪威尔总统的告别演讲。
Ah, okay.
啊，好的。
So a pretty famous...
所以是一个相当著名的……
Now we have to tell you that we did change the speech a little bit, right?
现在我们必须告诉你，我们确实对演讲做了一点改动，对吧？
Just a little bit to make it a little bit more understandable.
只是稍微改动，让它更容易理解。
But it's basically what he said to the nation back in 1969.
但基本上就是他在 1969 年对全国说的话。
Alright now, I will as well tell you that this is a pretty hard dialogue.
好了，我还要告诉你，这段对话相当难。
It is very hard because the structures are a little bit complicated and even to a certain
非常难，因为结构有点复杂，甚至在一定程度上
point a little bit poetic, right?
有点诗意，对吧？
So why are we taking this speech as our dialogue?
那我们为什么要用这个演讲作为对话呢？
What are we going to learn from this?
我们能从中学到什么？
Well, we're going to learn some structures and some words that you can use maybe on a
嗯，我们将学习一些结构和词汇，你可以在
resignation letter or maybe in a celebration you want to thank Pete for coming.
辞职信中使用，或者在庆祝活动中想感谢某人到来时使用。
Okay, so we're going to learn some pretty difficult vocabulary but also learn some really
好的，所以我们将学习一些相当难的词汇，但也学习一些非常
useful structures like you said you could use in a resignation letter or even in a formal
有用的结构，就像你说的，可以用在辞职信甚至你自己的正式
speech of your own.
演讲中。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, this presidential farewell speech is divided into two parts.
现在，这个总统告别演讲分为两部分。
So today we're going to do part one and then next time we'll finish the speech with part
所以今天我们做第一部分，下次我们完成演讲的第二部分。
two.
So let's listen to President Eisenhower as he says goodbye to the nation and we'll come
那么，让我们听听艾森豪威尔总统向全国告别，我们
back just in a little bit.
一会儿回来。
Good evening, my fellow Americans.
晚上好，我的美国同胞们。
Three days from now, after a century of service to our country, I shall lay down the responsibilities
三天后，在为我们的国家服务了一个世纪之后，我将卸下
of office as in a traditional and solemn ceremony, the authority of the presidency is vested
总统职责，如同在一个传统而庄严的仪式中，总统的权力被授予
in my successor.
我的继任者。
This evening I come to you with a message of leave taking and farewell and to share
今晚，我带着告别和辞行的话语来到你们面前，并与你们，
a few final thoughts with you, my countrymen.
我的同胞们，分享一些最后的想法。
Like every other citizen, I wish the new president and all who will labor with him, Godspeed.
像每个其他公民一样，我祝愿新总统和所有与他共事的人，一路顺风。
I pray that the coming years will be blessed with peace and prosperity for all.
我祈祷未来岁月将为所有人带来和平与繁荣。
Our people expect their president and the Congress to find essential agreement on questions
我们的人民期望总统和国会能在重大问题上找到基本共识，
of great importance, the wise resolution of which will better shape the future of our
这些问题的明智解决将更好地塑造我们
great nation.
伟大国家的未来。
My own relations with Congress began on a remote and tenuous basis when long ago a member
我与国会的关系始于遥远而薄弱的基础，当时很久以前，一位
of the Senate appointed me to West Point.
参议员任命我进入西点军校。
I then had the pleasure of building more intimate relationships with Congress during the war
然后，我有幸在战争期间和战后初期
and the immediate post-war period.
与国会建立了更密切的关系。
Finally, we have progressed to the mutually interdependent relationship we've had during
最后，我们发展到了过去八年中
these past eight years.
相互依存的关系。
Wow, so Eisenhower is a pretty good speaker, isn't he?
哇，所以艾森豪威尔是个相当不错的演讲者，不是吗？
A good speaker and well, he said a lot of really nice things when he was saying goodbye.
一个不错的演讲者，而且，他在告别时说了很多非常好的话。
Yeah, pretty inspiring, I thought.
是的，我觉得相当鼓舞人心。
Really inspiring and as we said, there were a couple of different and difficult words
真的很鼓舞人心，正如我们所说，有一些不同且困难的词汇
and phrases, so why don't we start right now with Language Takeaway.
和短语，所以我们为什么不现在开始“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, Eisenhower said that in three days he shall lay down the responsibilities.
嗯，艾森豪威尔说，三天后他将卸下职责。
To lay down the responsibilities.
卸下职责。
All right, lay down something.
好的，卸下某物。
Basically, we understand the verb to lay down, right?
基本上，我们理解动词“卸下”，对吧？
To put it down, to put it on the ground.
放下，放在地上。
Right, now he's using it with responsibilities which is a little bit strange but it's kind
对，现在他把它与“职责”连用，这有点奇怪，但有点像
of like a metaphor by saying lay down arms, to lay down your weapons.
一个比喻，就像说“放下武器”，放下你的武器。
Right, and you know what?
对，你知道吗？
This is a really common phrase that we would hear especially when we're talking about the
这是一个非常常见的短语，我们经常会听到，尤其是在谈论
end of a war or something like that.
战争结束之类的事情时。
To lay down your arms, lay down your weapons.
放下你的武器，放下你的武器。
Yeah, so here I think Eisenhower is kind of referencing this and giving us a little bit
是的，所以我认为艾森豪威尔在这里有点引用这个，并在他的演讲中
of poetry in his speech.
加入了一点诗意。
Right, so it's not that he's quitting, it's not that he's being fired, he's just like
对，所以不是他辞职，不是他被解雇，他只是
finishing what he started.
完成他开始的事情。
Yes, so he's laying down his responsibilities.
是的，所以他正在卸下他的职责。
Now, I think this would be quite an interesting phrase to use for example in a resignation
现在，我认为这是一个相当有趣的短语，例如可以在辞职信中使用。
letter.
Right, so I would say a month from now I will lay down my responsibilities as manager.
对，所以我会说，一个月后，我将卸下经理的职责。
Yep, all right, so that sounds pretty good.
是的，好的，听起来不错。
Now, he said he's going to be laying down the responsibilities in a traditional and
现在，他说他将在一个传统而庄严的仪式中卸下职责。
solemn ceremony.
All right, solemn.
好的，庄严。
Now, solemn, what does that mean?
现在，庄严，那是什么意思？
What is a solemn ceremony?
什么是庄严的仪式？
Well, a solemn ceremony would be a serious, respectful and a little bit sad ceremony.
嗯，庄严的仪式是一个严肃、尊重且有点悲伤的仪式。
Okay, so it's a serious matter and it's very respectful, right?
好的，所以这是一件严肃的事情，而且非常尊重，对吧？
Yeah, so you might say for example on the 11th of November when you're remembering the
是的，所以你可以说，例如在 11 月 11 日纪念战争时，
war you might say something like this is a very solemn day.
你可能会说这是一个非常庄严的日子。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay, and the authority of the presidency is vested in my successor.
好的，总统的权力被授予我的继任者。
Okay, so interesting verb.
好的，一个有趣的动词。
So interesting word, vested.
一个有趣的词，授予。
Vested.
授予。
The authority vested in my successor.
权力被授予我的继任者。
Very good.
非常好。
So this word basically means power that I have by law.
所以这个词基本上意味着我依法拥有的权力。
Right, so this power, this important power you have is given to you by the law, by the
对，所以这种权力，你拥有的这种重要权力是由法律、总统、
president, by the country.
国家赋予你的。
This is a very common word you will hear in a wedding when the priest or the person that's
这是一个非常常见的词，你会在婚礼上听到，当牧师或主持
leading the wedding will say by the power vested in me by the state of California.
婚礼的人会说，凭加利福尼亚州授予我的权力。
Yeah, I now pronounce you husband and wife.
是的，我现在宣布你们结为夫妻。
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
我现在宣布你们结为夫妻。
So he's saying the power that I have given to me by the state of California I can now
所以他说，加利福尼亚州授予我的权力，我现在可以
make you be married.
让你们结婚。
So here Eisenhower is saying the authority of the presidency is vested in my successor.
所以这里艾森豪威尔说，总统的权力被授予我的继任者。
So the power of the presidency will be given to the next president by law.
所以总统的权力将依法交给下一任总统。
Exactly.
没错。
And he also wished the new president and everyone with him, he said Godspeed.
他还祝愿新总统和所有与他一起的人，他说“一路顺风”。
All right, Godspeed.
好的，一路顺风。
Godspeed.
一路顺风。
I wish you Godspeed.
我祝你一路顺风。
Now, Godspeed, what does that mean?
现在，一路顺风，那是什么意思？
Well, it's kind of a blessing.
嗯，这是一种祝福。
It basically means good luck and good fortune.
它基本上意味着好运和好运气。
All right.
好的。
And especially in a journey.
尤其是在旅途中。
Yeah, I think you'd almost only use this when someone's going off on a big trip or a journey.
是的，我认为你几乎只在某人要踏上大旅行或旅程时才用这个词。
So here they're going on the journey of the presidency.
所以这里他们正在踏上总统职位的旅程。
Right.
对。
So I wish you Godspeed.
所以我祝你一路顺风。
Godspeed.
一路顺风。
Very good.
非常好。
And now let's take a look at our last set of words.
现在让我们看看最后一组词。
When he was talking about Congress, he said that his relation with Congress began on a
当他谈到国会时，他说他与国会的关系始于
remote and tenuous basis.
遥远而薄弱的基础。
All right.
好的。
So two interesting words here, remote and tenuous.
所以这里有两个有趣的词，遥远和薄弱。
Now, remote, we understand as being far away or distant.
现在，遥远，我们理解为遥远或疏远。
Yeah.
是的。
What about tenuous, though?
那薄弱呢？
But tenuous is kind of unimportant or not really relevant.
薄弱有点不重要或不太相关。
All right.
好的。
So actually, this is a pretty high quality, useful and smart sounding word.
所以实际上，这是一个相当高质量、有用且听起来很聪明的词。
So I think we should hear a few more examples of how it's used.
所以我认为我们应该多听几个例子，看看它是如何使用的。
Example one.
例子一。
How can you say the earth is actually getting cooler?
你怎么能说地球实际上在变冷？
That is a pretty tenuous argument.
那是一个相当薄弱的论点。
Example two.
例子二。
John believes that Elvis Presley is still alive.
约翰相信猫王还活着。
He's got a tenuous hold on reality.
他对现实的把握很薄弱。
Example three.
例子三。
You're making yourself seem more important than you are.
你让自己显得比实际更重要。
The connection between our company's success and your performance is tenuous at best.
我们公司的成功和你的表现之间的联系充其量是薄弱的。
All right.
好的。
So as we said, these are some pretty difficult words that we found in the dialogue.
所以正如我们所说，这些是我们在对话中发现的一些相当难的词。
But now I want to go and look at some really interesting formal structures that Eisenhower
但现在我想看看艾森豪威尔在这里使用的一些非常有趣的正式结构。
used here.
So let's look at those now in Fluency Builder.
那么现在让我们在“流利度构建”部分看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right.
好的。
On Fluency Builder today, we have three phrases.
在今天的流利度构建中，我们有三个短语。
And well, starting with the first one, I think it's one of the most interesting ones.
嗯，从第一个开始，我认为这是最有趣的之一。
He said, three days from now, after half a century of service of our country, I shall
他说，三天后，在为我们的国家服务了半个世纪之后，我将
lay down the responsibilities of office.
卸下总统职责。
All right.
好的。
So what's interesting about this?
那么这有什么有趣的呢？
If you take a look at the structure, he's saying three days from now, which is future,
如果你看一下结构，他说“三天后”，这是未来，
and then he makes a reference to the past after a half century of service.
然后他提到了过去，“在服务了半个世纪之后”。
Okay.
好的。
So we've got future past.
所以我们有未来过去。
And then again, future, I shall lay down the responsibilities.
然后又是未来，“我将卸下职责”。
All right.
好的。
So this actually is quite a good structure if you're giving a farewell speech or even
所以这实际上是一个相当好的结构，如果你在发表告别演讲，甚至
I could imagine using this at a wedding.
我可以想象在婚礼上使用它。
Right.
对。
How would you use it in a wedding?
你怎么在婚礼上使用它？
I might say, 12 hours for now after a long and beautiful relationship, this couple shall
我可能会说，12 小时后，在漫长而美好的关系之后，这对夫妇将
marry.
结婚。
Very good.
非常好。
So you're making reference to the future and then a past event or something that's been
所以你提到了未来，然后是一个过去的事件或已经
going on for a while and then future again.
持续了一段时间的事情，然后又是未来。
Why don't we do one more example?
我们为什么不举一个例子？
So for example, in a resignation letter, I can say, one month from now, after 30 years
例如，在辞职信中，我可以说，一个月后，在 30 年
of hard work and dedication to this company, I shall lay down my responsibilities as product
的辛勤工作和奉献之后，我将卸下产品经理的职责。
manager.
All right.
好的。
Interesting.
有趣。
So we can use it and it sounds good.
所以我们可以使用它，听起来不错。
It sounds very professional.
听起来非常专业。
And very poetic.
而且非常诗意。
Very poetic.
非常诗意。
It sounds nice.
听起来不错。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So that's a good structure.
所以这是一个好结构。
Now, why don't we go on to this next kind of very formal and helpful in a very formal
现在，我们为什么不继续下一个这种非常正式且在正式演讲中很有用的结构？
speech?
Well, President Eisenhower said, this evening I come to you with a message of leave taking
嗯，艾森豪威尔总统说，今晚我带着告别和辞行的话语来到你们面前。
and farewell.
So this evening I come to you with a message of leave taking and farewell.
所以今晚我带着告别和辞行的话语来到你们面前。
So it's a very nice way of saying, I'm talking to you today because I am saying goodbye.
这是一个很好的方式来说，我今天和你们说话是因为我在告别。
Yes.
是的。
And what I really like about this phrase is the beginning part.
我特别喜欢这个短语的开头部分。
This evening I come to you with a message of.
今晚我带着……的话语来到你们面前。
So again, let's suppose we're at a wedding.
所以再次，假设我们在一个婚礼上。
If I'm offering a toast or I'm the best man, I could say, this evening I come to you with
如果我在祝酒或我是伴郎，我可以说，今晚我带着
a message of love and trust and respect.
爱、信任和尊重的话语来到你们面前。
All right.
好的。
Or maybe if you're the leader of a company, you might say something like, this afternoon
或者如果你是公司的领导，你可能会说，今天下午
I come to you with a message of hope for the future.
我带着对未来希望的话语来到你们面前。
Very good.
非常好。
And now the part when he says leave taking and farewell, it's basically saying taking
现在，当他说“告别和辞行”时，基本上就是说
leave or taking like a vacation, right?
离开或像度假一样，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And farewell is goodbye.
而“辞行”就是再见。
And what about our last phrase?
那我们的最后一个短语呢？
This is actually a bit of a long one.
这实际上有点长。
So I'm going to read it now.
那么我现在要读一下。
Our people expect their president and the Congress to find essential agreement on questions
我们的人民期望总统和国会就重大问题达成基本共识，
of great importance, the wise resolution of which will better shape the future of our
这些问题的明智解决将更好地塑造我们伟大国家的未来。
great nation.
我们伟大国家的未来。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So let's take a look at the first part.
那我们来看看第一部分。
Basically he's saying the people expect the president and the Congress to give them answers,
基本上他在说，人民期望总统和国会给他们答案，
right?
对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
To agree on important issues.
在重要问题上达成一致。
But in the part when he says the wise resolution of which will better shape the future of our
但在他说的那部分，“这些问题的明智解决将更好地塑造我们伟大国家的未来”
great nation.
我们伟大国家的未来。
Yeah.
是的。
And this is the part I want to focus on.
而这就是我想重点讨论的部分。
The wise resolution of which.
“这些问题的明智解决”。
Now this is a really wonderful sort of formal structure.
这是一种非常精彩的正式结构。
So we can see what he's doing here.
所以我们可以看到他在做什么。
He's talking about the first idea, right?
他在谈论第一个观点，对吧？
So the president and the Congress need to find agreement on important issues, right?
所以总统和国会需要在重要问题上达成一致，对吧？
Now the wise resolution of which.
现在，“这些问题的明智解决”。
So he's referring back to that idea.
所以他是在回指那个观点。
So the wise resolution of what?
那么，什么的明智解决？
Of the essential agreement on questions of great importance.
关于重大问题的基本共识。
Right.
对。
So really useful structure.
所以这是一个非常有用的结构。
Why don't we hear a few more examples of this?
我们为什么不听听更多这样的例子呢？
Example one, we now face a great challenge, the overcoming of which lead us all to untold
例子一：我们现在面临一个巨大挑战，克服它将为我们所有人带来无尽的财富和成功。
riches and success.
财富和成功。
Example two, we as a company now face our most difficult months to date, the outcome
例子二：我们公司现在面临迄今为止最艰难的几个月，其结果将决定我们公司的未来。
of which will determine our company's future.
其结果将决定我们公司的未来。
Example three, the ambitious plan to reduce poverty, the start of which was launched last
例子三：那个雄心勃勃的减贫计划，其启动于上周二在纽约，将需要投入大量纳税人的钱。
Tuesday in New York, will require a huge investment of taxpayers' dollars.
将需要投入大量纳税人的钱。
All right.
好的。
So as you can hear from the examples, we have the main idea and then he passes on, but then
所以从这些例子中你可以听到，我们先提出主要观点，然后他继续往下说，但又回指了它。
kind of refers back to it again.
又回指了它。
Yeah.
是的。
And this sounds quite formal, but also quite literary and intelligent.
这听起来很正式，但也很有文学性和智慧感。
It makes you sound well-spoken.
这让你听起来很有口才。
Very good.
非常好。
This was quite a difficult dialogue with some really interesting and tricky structures and
这段对话相当难，里面有一些非常有趣且棘手的结构和词汇。
words.
词汇。
Let's hear it one more time all together.
让我们再完整地听一遍。
Good evening, my fellow Americans.
晚上好，我的美国同胞们。
Three days from now, after a century of service to our country, I shall lay down the responsibilities
三天后，在为我们的国家服务了一个世纪之后，我将卸任总统职责，如同传统而庄严的仪式中，总统的权力将移交给我的继任者。
of office as in a traditional and solemn ceremony, the authority of the presidency is vested
总统的权力将移交给我的继任者。
in my successor.
今晚，我向你们带来一个告别和离别的信息，并与你们分享一些最后的想法。
This evening, I come to you with a message of leave taking and farewell, and to share
与你们分享一些最后的想法。
a few final thoughts with you.
我的同胞们，像每一位公民一样，我祝愿新总统以及所有与他一起努力的人一帆风顺。
My countrymen, like every other citizen, I wish the new president and all who will labor
我祝愿新总统以及所有与他一起努力的人一帆风顺。
with him Godspeed.
我祈祷未来的岁月将为所有人带来和平与繁荣。
I pray that the coming years will be blessed with peace and prosperity for all.
Our people expect their president and the Congress to find essential agreement on questions
我们的人民期望总统和国会就重大问题达成基本共识，
of great importance, the wise resolution of which will better shape the future of our
这些问题的明智解决将更好地塑造我们伟大国家的未来。
great nation.
我们伟大国家的未来。
My own relations with Congress began on a remote and tenuous basis when, long ago, a
我与国会的关系始于很久以前，当时一位参议员任命我去西点军校，那是一种遥远而脆弱的基础。
member of the Senate appointed me to West Point.
一位参议员任命我去西点军校。
I then had the pleasure of building more intimate relationships with Congress during the war
后来，在战争期间和战后初期，我有幸与国会建立了更密切的关系。
and the immediate post-war period.
在战争期间和战后初期。
Finally, we have progressed to the mutually interdependent relationship we've had during
最后，我们发展到了过去八年中相互依存的关系。
these past eight years.
过去八年中相互依存的关系。
All right, we're back, and here with us in the studio we have Pete, the actor in the
好的，我们回来了，今天在演播室和我们一起的是皮特，他在对话中扮演了艾森豪威尔总统的告别演说。
dialogue of President Eisenhower's presidential farewell speech.
他在对话中扮演了艾森豪威尔总统的告别演说。
He's a pretty convincing actor at that.
他演得还挺有说服力的。
Not quite.
不太像。
So, Pete is going to give us a little bit of insight about President Eisenhower.
那么，皮特将给我们一些关于艾森豪威尔总统的见解。
All right, so what can you tell us about President Eisenhower?
好的，那么你能告诉我们关于艾森豪威尔总统的什么？
Well, he started off as a general.
嗯，他最初是一名将军。
He was an accomplished officer all through the early 20th century, and then he was the
他在20世纪早期是一位成就卓著的军官，后来成为二战中盟国远征军的最高指挥官。
supreme commander of the Allied Expeditionary Force in World War II.
后来成为二战中盟国远征军的最高指挥官。
And so now he's most famous for D-Day.
所以他最出名的是诺曼底登陆日。
He was leading it?
是他领导了那次行动吗？
Or he was on the battlefield?
还是他在战场上？
No, he was the organizer.
不，他是组织者。
He was kind of like the brains behind the operation.
他有点像行动背后的智囊。
Yeah.
是的。
I don't know if you want to leave this in, but there's a really cool document that he
我不知道你是否想保留这段，但他在入侵前写了一份非常酷的文件，上面说他基本上知道这次行动只有两种结果，他写了一份稿子以备失败时宣读。
wrote right before the invasion, and it said he basically knew this was going to go one
他写了一份稿子以备失败时宣读。
of two ways, and he wrote down a script to read in case it failed.
他基本上说，你知道，我很遗憾地通知你，入侵没有按计划进行，这使我们的战争努力受挫。
And he basically said, you know, I'm sorry to inform you that the invasion did not go
这使我们的战争努力受挫。
as planned, and this is setback our war effort.
当入侵顺利时，他把那份稿子扔进了垃圾桶，然后他的一名助手发现了它，惊叹道，哇，这是一份历史文件。
And when the invasion went well, he threw that in the trash, and then one of his aides
然后他的一名助手发现了它，惊叹道，哇，这是一份历史文件。
found that and was like, wow, this is a historical document.
然后他们保留了……
And they kept the...
哦，真的吗？
Oh, really?
是的。
Yeah.
所以他们保留了那份副本。
So they had the copy.
另一种历史。
Alternate history.
好的，所以他是一位成就卓著的将军，一位了不起的战士。
All right, so he was an accomplished general, an amazing warrior.
但他的总统任期呢？
But what about his presidency?
嗯，一开始，他做的最重要的事情可能就是结束了朝鲜战争，这是他在竞选期间做出的承诺。
Well, at the beginning, probably the biggest thing he did was to wrap up the Korean War,
这是他在竞选期间做出的承诺。
which was a vow he made during his campaign.
然后他访问了朝鲜。
And then he visited Korea.
显然，战争在技术上仍在继续，但他们确实安排了停火。
Obviously the war is still technically on, but they did arrange a ceasefire.
艾森豪威尔建立了州际公路系统，这是美国在20世纪经济成功的主要原因之一。
Eisenhower built up the interstate highway system, which is one of the big reasons that
这是美国在20世纪经济成功的主要原因之一。
America was able to become economically successful in the 20th century.
他这样做基本上是为了在战争发生时，我们可以方便地在全国范围内运送士兵和核武器。
He did it basically so that in case of a war, we'd have an easy way of shipping our soldiers
我们可以方便地在全国范围内运送士兵和核武器。
and nukes across the country.
但无论如何，它效果很好。
But it worked well anyways.
是的，这是那种附带好处的事情之一。
Yeah, it's one of these things that pays a side benefit.
至少他得用这种方式向国家推销它。
At least he had to sell it to the country that way.
他很可能从未打算那样使用它。
It's very likely that he didn't intend ever to use it that way.
但你必须……
But you have to have...
就像反恐战争一样。
It's like the war on terror.
你得推销这些东西。
You got to sell these things.
嗯，我想它不仅对各州的经济产生了巨大影响，还对文化以及人们对汽车及其社会影响的看法产生了巨大影响。
Well, and I guess it's had a huge impact not only on the economy of the states, but also
还对文化以及人们对汽车及其社会影响的看法产生了巨大影响。
like the culture and the way that people view the car and its effect on society.
确实如此。
Definitely.
所以这位艾森豪威尔是个相当有影响力的人。
So pretty influential guy, this Eisenhower.
是的，而且是一堂很有历史意义的课。
Yeah, and a very historical lesson.
这只是关于文化的一点内容，也许是对美国历史的一些见解。
It's just a little bit of a culture and maybe some insight on American history.
并不是说我们政治上活跃什么的，但是的，那里有一些有趣的信息。
It's not like we're politically active or anything, but yeah, it was some interesting
那里有一些有趣的信息。
information there.
而且，嗯，他被认为是一位相当不错的总统。
And also, well, he was considered to be a pretty good president.
是的，他的评价，我不会说排在前五名左右，但相当有成就。
Yeah, he's rated, I wouldn't say among the top five or so, but quite accomplished.
嗯，也许不是我们见过的最伟大的总统，但他写了一篇相当不错的告别演说。
Well, maybe not the greatest president we've ever seen, but he wrote a pretty good farewell
但他写了一篇相当不错的告别演说。
speech.
所以我想我们得为此感谢他。
So I think we have that to thank him for.
好的，各位，如果你们还有其他问题或评论，可以访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在那里给艾丽卡或我留言。
All right, guys, so if you have any other questions or comments, you can come to the
在那里给艾丽卡或我留言。
website at EnglishPod.com and you can leave them there for Erica or I.
好的，谢谢你们的下载，下次再见，再见。
Okay, so thanks for downloading you guys and until next time, goodbye.
再见。
Bye.